# Francisco (Paco) Muro

Birth date and place: Feb 1993, Madrid, Spain

Based in: Cologne, Germany E-Mail: <a href="mailto:fco.muro2@gmail.com">fco.muro2@gmail.com</a>

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/francisco-paco-muro-006a7895/

Website: https://fcomuro2.wixsite.com/website

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

With a background in Aerospace Engineering, Software Development and Entrepreneurial studies, I'm excited to join innovative and leading edge technology projects. I want to release my creative potential and take advantage of my multidisciplinary skills to make a greater impact, while ready to be surprised, curious about new knowledge and taking ownership of my results.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Silexica** – Cologne, Germany Agile Project Management

08/2018 -10/2019 (internship, master thesis)

- ✓ Planning and implementing agile adoption✓ Enacting change and continuous improvement
- Enacting change and continuous improvementSeveral responsibilities, "wearing different hats"
- ✓ Jira/Bitbucket Admin + backend automation scripting

SILEXICA **\*\*\*\*** 

03/2017 - **Tadorea** – Madrid, Spain

07/2017 Airspace Data Infrastructure Engineer

- ✓ R&D of Air Traffic Analysis tools
- ✓ Development of runway allocation software
- ✓ Analysis of airspace and runway usage

TADOREA KNOWLEDGE DISCOVERY FOR AVIATION

09/2016 -02/2017 (internship) National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) -

NASA Ames, CA, USA - Human Systems Integration Division

- ✓ Data analysis and software development supporting research on Air Traffic Management tools
- ✓ Running human-in-the-loop simulations for data collection of innovative ATM tool



03/2016 -

The Innaxis Foundation & Research Institute – Madrid, Spain

07/2016

✓ Decoding ADS-B signals

(internship)

✓ Studying opportunities and feasibility for ATM analysis



12/2015 - 02/2016 (internship)

Deutsches Zentrum für Luft- und Raumfahrt (DLR) -

Braunschweig, Germany - Institut für Flugführung

- ✓ Research of GNSS Based Relative Navigation for Intentional Approximation of Aircraft
- Implementation of algorithms and analysis of experiments



## **EDUCATION**

2017-2019 **Aalborg University (AAU)** – Aalborg, Denmark

Master in Entrepreneurial Engineering

Thesis title: "A method to improve and adopt agility in growing organizations: a high-tech software company case study"



2014-2015 **Technische Universität Braunschweig (TU BS)** – Germany

(Erasmus, Bachelor of Science: Luft- und Raumfahrttechnik

2 semesters) (Erasmus exchange program)



2013-2014 Nanyang Technological University (NTU) – Singapore

(Exchange, Bachelor of Science: Aerospace engineering

2 semesters) (International exchange program)



2011-2017 Universidad Carlos III de Madrid (UC3M) – Spain

Bachelor of Science: Aerospace engineering

(Issuer of the bachelor title)



**Languages** Spanish – Native

English – Fluent (2017: TOEFL score; 109/120 or C1+)

German – Fluent (finished B2 course at the Volkshochschule Braunschweig in 2015)

IT Skills MS Office: Very good

Programming: Matlab, Python, Java, JavaScript, C++, Groovy Agile: Atlassian Jira/Bitbucket Admin, Scriptrunner

FEM: SolidWorks Fluent CAD: Siemens Solid Edge

Audio: Ableton Live, Bitwig, Native Instruments

### PERSONAL PROFILE

Music Amateur experience in the field of electronic music composing, synthesizers, recording

and playback devices, designing spaces for sound treatment, DJ professionally.

Interactive Another way to fulfill my urge of closing the gap between inert technology and human Digital Arts psychology is to code and build interactive visual arts. As a hobby I design and

implement physical light installations, wearables and IoT lighting solutions. It's absolutely

fulfilling and mesmerizing.

International As a kid I spent a year in a boarding school in **England**. Ever since I felt very independent experience and responsible for myself. During high school I took part on two different exchange

and responsible for myself. During high school I took part on two different exchange programs in **the Netherlands** and **New York City**. During my exchange in **Singapore** I had the chance to explore other southeastern Asian cultures. Knowing I would do Erasmus exchange in **Braunschweig, Germany**, I spent that summer learning German in **Berlin**. Taking my last lectures back in **Madrid** felt like a new beginning rather than coming back. The internship at NASA and living in **Silicon Valley** was one of the most fulfilling experiences of my life. During my master studies in **Denmark** I developed and practiced exciting skills that will be key for the future of my career, as for my personality. Currently I live in **Cologne**, which offers me a very satisfying stage of my life for self introspection and bonding with diverse and open-minded individuals.